fring.com 2007-12-24

# fring - privacy policy.

Privacy Policy of fring™

Thank you for visiting [http://www.fring.com](http://www.fring.com/) (the "Site") (together with the fring network, the fring software, all other services offered and websites operated directed or indirectly by fringland Ltd., the "Site and Services") Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") explaining our online information practices and those related to use of fring downloadable software, and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used at the Site and Services. This Privacy Policy forms part of the Terms of Use, which are binding on you and are available at <http://www.fring.com/terms/>. If you download or use any of fring’s Site and Services, you agree to be bound by the fring software end-user license, available at <http://www.fring.com/license/>. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use of the Site and Services following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you accept those changes. 

Introduction

We are committed to respecting your online privacy and recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") you share with us or which is available to us through the Site and Services. Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, personal profile, a home or other physical address, a phone number and an email address or other contact information. The fring user identification (the "UserID") is your mobile phone number and/or an additional identifier that you may choose. 

When you use the Site or Services, we may record information about your usage. 

We may transfer your Personal Information within fring or to fring's third-party service providers and business partners, but only to provide services on the Site and Services or to you, across borders, and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. To the extent that fring "co-brands" an internet page, or product or service with another party, the Personal Information that you choose to provide to such co-branded service will be handled by either party and in accordance with this policy for fring, and the third party’s policy. A "co-branded" page or service is one which bears both the fring and third party names, branding, graphics or anything else which makes it clear that you are viewing a co-branded service. Please be sure to read fring’s and the partner’s privacy policies before entering or providing information to a co-branded page or service. 

Uses

We use and store the Personal Information we collect internally to: 

| | | | deliver the best possible service to you, such as improving the fring software user interface and maintaining a consistent and reliable user experience;   
---|---|---|---  
| | |  Provide you personalized content and advertisements;   
| | | Fulfill your requests for products, programs and services;   
| | | Communicate with you and respond to your inquiries;   
| | |  Conduct research about your use of the Site and Services;   
| | |  Check your version of the fring software and download upgrades so that you have the most current version and   
| | |  Help offer you other products or services that may be of interest to you.   
  
People included in your contact list may be able to see your online presence (including whether you are mobile), username, and any information that you choose to add to your profile, including images, links, and custom status indicators. Other users may add you to their contact list by specifying your mobile phone number or other userID. fring may also provide that your online presence (including whether you are mobile) is indicated in other programs used by Users. When you use fring software, fring may include a message indicating such usage. 

fringME! widget

If You elect to use our "fringME! widget" service You need to have a private page ("Private Page") where You placed the "fringME! widget" (such as Your blog or Your page on a social networking site). The fringME! widget service will, at Your discretion, allow You: (i) to chat online with anyone who visits Your Private Page, (ii) to enable Your Private Page visitors to see Your fring mobile presence, (iii) to see where You are located, using real-time location information, based on, or transmitted by, Your mobile device's location; and/or (iv) to choose other features that fring makes available as part of the fringME! widget service from time to time. To provide the fringME! widget, we may collect, maintain, use, and display, Your personal data, Your fring mobile presence and the real-time geographic location of Your mobile device and other information we notify You of (we call this "Data"). In registering for the fringME! widget service, You have agreed and consented to fring's collection, use, maintenance, and display of Your Data in order to provide all of the services, features, and functionality found within the fringME! widget service. We will obtain Your express consent to collect, maintain, use, and display Your Data and other information as part of providing the fringME! widget service. You have the right at any time to deny or withdraw Your consent to the disclosure of Your Data. Your denial of consent will prevent You from using the specific feature of the fringME! widget service which You elect not to use. In order to withdraw Your consent which will prevent others from seeing Your presence, disable the service in Your "fring client". 

Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Some of our Site pages utilize "cookies" and other tracking technologies. A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about Site activity. Some cookies and other technologies may serve to recall Personal Information previously indicated by a Site user. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. 

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you will need to re-enter certain identifying information, should we in the future require such information, to gain access to certain parts of the Site. 

Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clickstream patterns; and dates and times that our Site is accessed. Our use of cookies and other tracking technologies allows us to improve our Site and your web experience. 

To protect your privacy, we have adopted the following principles which are specified below: 

| | | Notice   
---|---|---|---  
| | | Choice  
| | | Security   
| | | Access/Accuracy   
  
Notice

We do not provide your Personal Information to third parties, except for third parties who may perform services for the Site or Services, and except that fring may also permit access to your UserID or telephone number to permit other Users to add you as a friend. fring does not intend to transfer Personal Information without your consent to third parties who are not bound to act on fring's behalf unless such transfer is legally required. Nevertheless, in the context of a sale or transfer of all or part of our assets to a third party, your Personal Information may be one of the transferred assets. 

Regardless of your decision regarding the sharing of your Personal Information, we may share broad aggregate demographic data and related usage information with our business partners. This aggregate information does not contain any Personal Information that can identify an individual user. 

Choice

By using the fring software, you agree to make available your phone number to fring. You may choose whether or not to provide additional Personal Information to fring. If you choose not to provide the additional Personal Information we request, you can still use most of the Site and Services, but you may be unable to access certain services. 

Security 

We have implemented reasonable security policies, rules and technical measures to protect and safeguard the Personal Information under our control from unauthorized access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorized modification, unlawful destruction or accidental loss. Nevertheless, fring is not liable for any damages resulting from any security breaches, or unauthorized and/or fraudulent use of your User identification information. All our employees and data processors that have access to, and are associated with the processing of your Personal Information, may have access to your Personal Information and random usage traffic, and are obliged to respect the confidentiality of your information. Please be sure to keep your userID and password secure since this is necessary to retrieve your previous contact list, should you change phones. 

Access/Accuracy

fring wishes to make sure that your Personal Information is accurate. You may check your profile and contact us at  www.fring.com/support to add information, correct any incorrect information and delete information (except for the UserID). 

Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites

Our Site may use a reputable third party to present or serve advertisements that you may see at our Site. These third party ad servers may use cookies, web beacons, clear gifs or similar technologies to help present such advertisements, and to help measure and research the advertisements' effectiveness. The use of these technologies by these third party ad servers is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by our Privacy Policy. 

Links to Other Sites

Our Site may contain links to other sites. Other sites may also reference or link to our Site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. 

Commitment

We are committed to protecting your privacy. Protecting your privacy online is an evolving area, and fring's Site and Services are constantly evolving to meet these demands. If you have any comments or questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@fring.com](mailto:privacy@fring.com). While we cannot guarantee privacy perfection, we will address any issue to the best of our abilities as soon as possible. 

Your Consent

By using any of the Site and Services, you consent to the terms of our Privacy Policy and to fring's processing of Personal Information for the purposes given above. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use any of our Site and Services. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this Privacy Policy at any time. Your continued use of any of our Site and Services following the posting of changes to these terms means you accept these changes. 

Your California Privacy Rights

fring's Privacy Policy is to share personal information only with the owner's informed consent. With your consent, from time-to-time, fring may provide its business partners with contact details for direct marketing purposes of relevant services, products, and programs. If you no longer wish your information to be shared, please let us know. If you have further inquires regarding fring's Information Sharing Practices, please let us know. The designated contact for these queries is [privacy@fring.com](mailto:privacy@fring.com). 

Last modified: November 20, 2007
